Guide to the Robert Hofstadter Papers SC0426
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2008-003
  - Publications and Writings
    - Iron Free Solenoidal Spectrometer, National Science Foundation proposal, 1960 Dec (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Reprints, 1947-1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Reprints, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Articles, Various, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Working File for Bibliography Creation, circa 1938-1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Reprints, various, 1938-1986 (Box 1, Folder 20-22)
    - Bibliography Abstracts, 1938-1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Neutron," World Book Encyclopedia, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Measurements", undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Some Electromagnetic Characteristics of a Parallel Wire System", 1934 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "On the Infrared Absorption by Light and Heavy Formic and Acidic Acids, with Special Regard to the Problem of the Hydrogen Bond" (Dissertation), 1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "First Semi-annual Technical Summary Report -- Energy Loss Mechanisms of Particles in Semiconductors" (ARPA no. 213), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Publications, Molecular Spectra (with B. Herman), circa 1938 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "The Atomic Nucleus", circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "Simultaneity in the Compton Effect", circa 1949 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - "The Structure of the Proton" (with E. E. Chambers), circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Publications by year, volume 1 (#1-27), 1938-1948 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Publications by year, volume 1 (#28-46), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Publications by year, volume 2 (#47-81), 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Publications by year, volume 3 (#82-104), 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Publications by year, volume 3 (#105-137), 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Publications by year, volume 4 (#138-158), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Publications by year, volume 4 (#159-180), 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - SLAC Report no. 25, 1963 summer (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - SLAC Report no. 62, 1966 May (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - SLAC Report no. 5, 1962 summer (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Two-Mile Linear Electron Accelerator, proposal, 1957 April (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Energy Loss and Range of Electrons and Positrons (National Bureau of Standards Circular 577), 1956 July (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Physical Research Program, Hearings Before the Subcommittee on Research and Development of the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy Congress of the United States, 1958 Feb (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Stanford Linear Electron Accelerator, Hearings before the Subcommittee on R&D and Background Information Report to Joint Committee on Atomic Energy, 1959 Jul (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Aborted Manuscript, Nuclear and Nucleon Structure, figures and notation, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Various publications, 1950-1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "Experiemental Rate of Climb and Dice Meter (VH Meter)," Norden Labs, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Reprints, circa 1939-1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Interactions of Electrons with Nucleon and Nuclei, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Reprints, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
      Also includes correspondence, research notes, drafts, and related documents.
    - Reprints, 1960-1964 (Box 3, Folder 9-11)
    - Reprints, circa 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "Quantum Electrodynamics in Electron-Positron Systems", 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure," technical book draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "Atomic Acceleration", 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "On the Detection of 50 MeV y-Rays with a Large Modularized NaI(T1) Detector," HEPL 816, draft by multiple authors, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Proposals, list, 1965-1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Also includes some copies of proposals
    - "Quantum Electronic Dynamics in Electron-Positron Systems" (HEPL Report no. 768), 1975 Aug (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Study of Rare Muon Decays, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Continuation of High Energy Physics Program, proposal to National Science Foundation, 1979 Oct (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Reprints, multiple languages, 1949, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - "The Atomic Accelerator," HEPL Report no. 560, 1968 Apr (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Reprints, circa 1949-1977 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
    - "A Proposal for a Large Solid Angle Neutral Detector for SPEAR-II (The Crystal Ball)," SLAC Proposal SP-24, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Playboy Inc., Rejection Fee Check Stub for Non-Publication of "The Instant Electorate", 1967 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "Nucleons and Nuclei" manuscript and correspondence, Educational Services Inc., 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Angiography reprints with index, 1981-1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Reprints with index, various, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
    - Reprints with index, various, 1986-1990 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Nuclear Science vol. NS-17, IEEE Symposium publication, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Reprints, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Reprints, circa 1959-1987 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Calcium Isotopes, publications and notes, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - "A Search for the Rare Decay..." (D. P. Grosnick thesis study), 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Publications, submission copies and publisher correspondence, 1960-1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "Munich Paper," German translation of Crystal Ball, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - National Science Foundation proposal for high-energy physics, cryogenic research, gravitational research, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - Proposals, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7-9)
    - Proposals, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Proposals, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Proposals, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
    - Proposals, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Proposals, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Proposal, Office of Naval Research, Contract Continuation, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Proposal for High Energy Physics Program, National Science Foundation, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Proposals, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Proposals, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Proposals, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
    - "K-Edge Subtraction Report," National Institute of Health, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "Spark Chamber," draft, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - SAAC Support for Weizmann Institute Physicists, draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Dan Menelowitz obituary, draft, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Atomic Accelerant Project proposal, circa 1968 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Publications, various, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Publications, various, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Publications, various, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Publications, various, numbers 342-355 (index included), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Publications, various, numbers 356-368 (index included), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Bibliography, research notes, and related materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Publications, various, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Bibliography Research, notes and other materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Book for High School Students on Nucleon and Nuclear Structure, manuscript, circa 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Publication re: Bill Fairbank, correspondence drafts, and clippings, circa 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - National Science Foundation, High Energy Physics Program continuation proposal, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - National Science Foundation, proposal for study of rare muon decay at Los Alamos Lab, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - National Science Foundation proposal supplement, High Energy Physics Program continuation, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Publications, various, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Publications, various, 1978-1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Publications re: Decay of Muon, Meson, 1979-1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "Quantum Electrodynamics in Electron-Positron Systems", 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Reprints, 1965-1969 (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
    - Institute of Laser Engineering, Osaka University, Japan, Annual Progress Report, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Institute of Laser Engineering, Osaka University, Japan, Annual Progress Report, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Publication re: Fusion, L'Express (French), copy and clipping, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "Cross Strands Linking Physics and Medicine," drafts, notes, and reprints, circa 1983 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Publications, Volume 5, with index, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Publications, Volume 6, with index, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Publication, Volume 7, with index, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
    - Publications, Volume 8, with index, 1972-1974 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    - Publications. Volume 9, with index, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
    - Publications, Volume 10, with index, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
    - Leonard Schiff, Physics Today article and booklet with tribute by Hofstadter, 1965, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - SLAC/MIT/CIT Election Scattering Experiment Proposals, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Angiography
      - National Institute of Health proposal, "K-Edge Subtraction Angiography with Synchrotron X-Rays", 1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Department of Energy proposal, "Support in Evaluation of K-Edge Subtraction Angiography with Synchrotron X-Rays", 1983 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - "A New Approach to Coronary Angiography," drafts, circa 1983 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Synchrotron Radiation Handbook, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Electron Scattering
      - "A Personal View of Nucleon Structure as Revealed by Electron Scattering", circa 1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Electron scattering, draft manuscript with notes, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - "New Experiments of 248.2 and 502.0 MeV Electron Scattering by Pb 208, and New Information about its Charge Distribution," draft and notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Book Jacket Advertisement for High Energy Electron Scattering Tables, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - "Linear Accelerator and Scattering -- Gamma-Ray (Experiments)," HEPL report no. 126, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Two-Spectrometer System for High-Energy Electron Scattering Studies, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - "Electron Scattering off the Proton and X-Particle", circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Electron Scattering, various publications, circa 1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - "Electron Scattering from Neighboring Nuclei," technical report, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - "Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure," notebook and draft, circa 1959 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - "High Energy Electron Scattering Tables," correspondence re: publication, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - "A Personal View of Nucleon Structure as Revealed by Electron Scattering", 1988 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - NASA, EGRET, and GAMMA Rays
      - PULSAR drafts, research, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - "The Detection of Gamma-Rays with Thallium Activated Sodium Iodide Crystals", circa 1948 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - "Instrument Development for the Study of High Energy Gamma Rays in Space", 1979 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Gamma-Ray Astrophysics -- A New Look at the Universe," NASA Technical Memorandum 78103, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - "The Energetic Gamma-Ray Experiment Telescope (EGRET) Science Symposium," NASA Publication 3071, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - "Near Zero," edited manuscript and correspondence, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - High Energy Astronomical Observation (HEAO), correspondence, proposal and related documents, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - NASA Proposal, Experiment on High Energy Gamma-Ray Astronomy, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - NASA Proposal, Continued Study of Coded Aperture Systems, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - GRO and Gamma-Rays, publications, circa 1978-1988 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - NASA Information Kit, Gamma-Ray Observatory, circa 1991 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Scintillation
      - "Crystal and Scintillation Counters," unpublished manuscript, circa 1949 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - "Sodium Iodide as Scintillator," galley proofs, circa 1949 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - "Alkali Halide Scintillation Counters", 1948 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - "Sixth Scintillation Counter Symposium," IRE Transactions in Nuclear Science, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - "Scintillations in Aromatic Crystals," draft written at Princeton, circa 1940s (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - "Twenty-Five Years of Scintillation Counting," HEPL Report no. 749, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - "The Inception of Photoelectric Scintillation Detection Commemorated after Three Decades," article featuring Hofstadter's work from Journal of Nuclear Medicine, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - "Scintillation Counter," copies, correspondence, and drafts, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - "Behavior of Thallium Bromide Conduction Counters," reprint, correspondence, and figures, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Scintillators, publications, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Research
    Includes drafts, notes, lab notebooks, raw data, graphical representations of findings, reports, proposals, and related documents. Also included are materials collected by or sent to Hofstadter due to their relation to his research, as well as related correspondence. Researchers should note that additional proposals may be found in Publications and Writings.
    - Books on Order, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Books on Order, 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - HEPL Data Notebook No. 21, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Team Lab Nucleon Talk", photographs and figures, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "The Structure of the Proton," HEPL Report no. 77, draft, research data, notes, and correspondence, 1953-1956 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Data Concepts on Proton and Neutron Form Factors, early ideas, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Deuteron," data and concepts, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Cosmic Ray MESONS, data and notes, circa 1951 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure, Air Force contract status reports, 1954-1956 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Figures, circa 1958 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Notebook, circa 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Notebook, circa 1949-1954 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Notebook, CERN, proton form factors, circa 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Notebook, notes from Palmer Physics Lab, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Notebook, circa 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Notebook, Palmer Physics Lab, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Notes and Figures, circa 1950 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Notes and Figures, circa 1955 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Notebook: draft of "The Atomic Nucleus," correspondence to editor, 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Notebook: research notes on electron scattering, concentrating on large magnets for spectrometers, 1951-1953 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Cavendish Experiment, notes, figures and findings re measuring strength of gravity, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Notebook, circa 1950-1951 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Notebook: nip chambers, electron scattering, circa 1956 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Notebook, circa 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Notebook, circa 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Notebook, circa 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Notebook, circa 1954-1956 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Notebook, circa 1956 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Notebook: Nuclear Physics 185, etc., 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Notebook: Nuclear Physics 185, 187, etc., circa 1953-1955 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Notebook, circa 1960 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Notebook, 1960-1961 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Notebook, circa 1958-1961 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Notebook: SFM log, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Notebook, circa 1956-1958 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - "Figures for Book" (models, charts, and supporting text), 1965 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Isotope Form Factors and Neutron Form Factors, circa 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Progress Reports, Contract AF 18(600)-646 (Air Force), 1964-1957 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "Study of an Iron Free Solenoidal Spectrometer," technical drawings, circa 1961 (Box 11, Folder 3-5)
    - C12 Elasticity Research, notes, data, and drafts, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Magnetic Spectrometer, Hansen Lab, photographs and clippings, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Proposals, various, circa 1957-1964 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Magnetic Spectrometer Design, technical drawings, correspondence, notes, and related documents, circa 1965 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - National Science Foundation proposal and contract, x-ray detector development, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Magnetic Spectrometers, proposals and drawings, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Phase Shift Calculations, circa 1957 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Nuclear Trends, Middle and Heavy Z, data and related publications, 1955-1956 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Form Factors, graphs and illustrations, 1953-1960 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Crystals and Crystal Showers, circa 1953 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Naval Gun Mount for Electron Scattering, correspondence and technical drawings, circa 1953-1958 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Modern Physics Laboratory, various course documents, circa 1951-1953 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Supplies, purchase orders and correspondence, 1952-1963 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - 72 inch spectrometer, design and photographs, circa 1959 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Padua University, Italy, research correspondence, circa 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Proton uniform model and Yukawa model, raw data, notes, and figures, 1956-1958 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Palmer Physics Lab, Princeton -- HCOOD, CH3COOD, circa 1938 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Unpublished work -- notes, drafts, data, and correspondence, 1942-1946 (Box 11, Folder 23-24)
    - Atomic Power, research and correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Frank Hertz Tube, research, correspondence, and related documents, 1941-1942 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Notebook: Nuclear Physics and Relativity, 1936-1937 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Notebook, circa 1936 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Notebooks, I, II, III, circa 1937 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Notebook: Physics 15, City College of New York, circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Notebook: Analytical Mechanics, circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Notebook: Physics 14, Modern Physics, circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Notebook: Thermodynamics, circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Notebook, circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Notebook: Chemistry 3, circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Notebooks: CERN and Felix Bloch paper outline, 1959, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Los Alamos Scientific Lab, Laser Fusion, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Lawrence Livermore Labs, Laser Fusion, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Conference on detectors, notes, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - New High Energy Particle Detector, correspondence and related documents, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - DICOL Project, Synthetic Diamonds, circa 1985 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - "Nucleon and Nuclear Structure," presentation, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - National Science Foundation preliminary proposal, helmet camera, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Voting Booths, Fall Joint Computer Conference, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - "The Instant Electorate" (article for Playboy on voting booths, never published), notes and drafts, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Proposals and contracts, various, 1956-1978 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - National Science Foundation proposals, continuation of HEPL research, 1980-1986 (Box 12, Folder 18-19)
    - National Science Foundation proposals and correspondence, 1976-1986 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - "Final Technical Report," HEPL report to National Science Foundation, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - National Accelerator Lab proposals, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - National Science Foundation, Muon Decay proposal and correspondence, circa 1979-1984 (Box 12, Folder 23-24)
    - Los Alamos Scientific Lab, Rare Muon Decay proposals and memos, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - National Science Foundation proposal, US-USSR Joint Experiments -- Fermilab, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Rare Muon Decays, budget documents and correspondence, circa 1980-1984 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - National Science Foundation, final technical reports, 1978-1986 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Department of Energy proposal, Study of Acceleration Processes Produced by Excited Atoms, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - 180 degree scattering, photographs and negatives, 1962-1964 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Scattering off of Nuclei, data, circa 1952-1954 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "Elastic Scattering" (with gold), data, circa 1958 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - "The Structure of Nucleons and Atomic Nuclei Determined by High Energy Electron Scattering," HEPL Report no. 83, research and notes, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - "Elastic Scattering from the Proton and the Alpha Particle," data, correspondence, and related documents, 1954-1955 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Early Development of Election Scattering, results by others, circa 1948-1955 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Electron Scattering, draft proposal for contract with Office of Scientific Research, 1950-1952 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Electron Scattering, correspondence and notes, 1953-1954 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Electron Scattering, early data and results, 1953-1954 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Electron Scattering, data and results, correspondence and related documents, 1958-1968 (Box 13, Folder 10-11)
    - Electron Scattering, notes, figures, and related documents, 1955-1963 (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
    - Electron Scattering, notes for publication, figures, and correspondence, circa 1956 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Known Elements, Systematically Scattered and Graphed, Volume I, figures, undated (Box 13, Folder 15-16)
    - Known Elements, Systematically Scattered and Graphed, Volume I, figures, undated (Box 13, Folder 17-18)
    - Electron Scattering of the Alpha Particle, data, figures, notes, and related documents, 1953-1954 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Office of Naval Research proposal, "Electron Scattering and Nuclear Research," Hansen Labs, 1952-1956 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Electron Scattering Off Protons (=Hydrogen Nucleus), early results, data, figures, and related publications, circa 1954 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Fermilab proposal, scattering, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Inelastic Scattering in the Continuum, correspondence and related publications, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - High Energy Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure Determinations, data, drawings, and publications, 1951-1953 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Electron Scattering (Proton), research, correspondence, and press releases, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Electron Scattering, photographs, correspondence, and related documents, circa 1957 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Scattering, data, figures, and notes, circa 1956 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Unpublished Book on Scintillation Counters, circa 1951 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Discovery of Scintillation Properties for Sodium Iodide, reprints, notes and speches, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Air force grant proposal, X-Ray Detection in Semiconductors and Scintillators, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Synchrotron Radiation, proposal drafts, publications, notes, and related documents, circa 1984 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Synchrotron, circa 1988 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Henry J. Kaiser Family Foundation proposal, Angiography and Synchrotron Radiation, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Explorer Gamma-Ray Experiment Telescope (EGRET), proposals, correspondence, notes, and related documents, circa 1970-1975 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - "Gamma-Ray Observatory, Instrument System Concept Review of the Energetic Gamma-Ray Experiment Telescope", 1980 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Design and Interface Specification for Electronic System Total Absorption Shower Counter (TASC,) High Energy Gamma-Ray Telescope, Gamma-Ray Observatory, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 4)